SPENCER HAYES-LAVERDIÈRE

Montreal, Canada · 438-407-5805

spencer.hayes@meiacademy.com· in/spencerhayeslaverdiere · https://spencer-hayes.me/

Passionate data scientist and machine learning engineer with experience solving real-world problems in computer-vision, natural language processing, and finance. Currently leading the data initiative at a retail tech startup focused on scan-and-go and autonomous checkouts.

EXPERIENCE

2021 - CURRENT

DATA SCIENTIST & MANAGER, <u>LEAV</u>

- Led the development and deployment of a real-time recommendation system.
- Designed and integrated a robust data pipeline to store anonymized app usage data in a data lake.
- Developed and deployed a dashboard API capable of serving historical metrics to hundreds of stores simultaneously.

MAY 2021 - SEP 2021

DATA SCIENTIST – CONTRACT PART-TIME, ANAGRAPH

- Provided data analyses to clients with a specialization in geospatial data.
- Developed custom location intelligence tools.
- Improved in-house data science practices and tooling.

2020 - 2021

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, SQUAREFEET.AI

- Led the development of pricing algorithms and models.
- Integrated explainable AI tools such as SHAP to give insights on models and track metrics like class bias on model performance.
- Trained and deployed cloud models through AWS' SageMaker.

2018 - 2020

INSTRUCTOR, UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA

- Taught enrichment courses in Electrical & Computer Engineering
- Led in-school workshops teaching young kids engineering skills such as coding and 3D printing

SKILLS

- Bilingual (English/French)
- Statistics/Machine Learning: Statistical Analysis, Linear/Logistic Regression, Clustering, Encoding/Decoding, CNNs, RNNs
- Data tools: Python, Java, C, FPGA, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, AWS, GCP, Git, DVC, Linux
- Explainable AI: SHAP, LIME

ARTICLES

Finding Seasonal Trends in Time-Series Data with Python. Towards Data Science. Jun 7, 2021

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

BASC COMPUTER ENGINEERING (CO-OP), UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA

Minor in Business Management & Entrepreneurship.

Capstone: Land-robot and aerial drone co-operative autonomous system.